Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Research Department records, 1941-1983 IBT0010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Research Department records
1907-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0010
8.25 Linear Feet
This collections contains the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Research Department records dating from 1941-1983. The majority of the material pertains to research conducted by the IBT's Research Department into various companies and their contracts. The materials include correspondence, copies of labor contracts, statistics, reports, news clippings, hearing transcripts.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: Company Files, Senate Hearings, History Files, State Historical Society of Wisconsin Files, and Reports.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collections contains the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Research Department records dating from 1941-1983. The majority of the material pertains to research conducted by the IBT's Research Department into various companies and their contracts. The materials include correspondence, copies of labor contracts, statistics, reports, news clippings and photographs.
The collection also contains materials produced by the Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations dating from February 17 - November 3, 1981. Included are full hearing transcripts as well as reports and individual statement transcripts. Investigation topics include organized crime in the waterfront industry and government efforts to combat labor racketeering.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by IBT, 2012 [2012.005, 2012.055.]
Biographical / Historical
The IBT Research Department was a department of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters between 1941 and 1983. The purpose of the department was to conduct research of companies associated with the Teamsters and political affairs.
Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Crime; Labor
- Company Files, 1941-1983; Series 1; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by company name.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials dating from 1941-1983 related to research conducted by the IBT's Research Department into various companies and their contracts. The materials include correspondence, copies of labor contracts, statistics and reports, news clippings and photographs.
  - Boise Cascade Company, 1966; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borden Company, 1956; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burton-Dixie Corporation, 1956; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Campbell Soup Company [1/3], 1963-1964; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Campbell Soup Company [2/3], 1963-1968; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Campbell Soup Company [3/3], 1968-1977; Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - F.M. Stamper Company, 1957-1971; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kroger Company [1/4], 1954-1959; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kroger Company [2/4], 1958-1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kroger Company [3/4], 1953-1957; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Kroger Company [4/4], 1953-1974; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company (3M), 1966-1969; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Omar Bakeries, 1963-1966; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - REA Express [1/2], 1966-1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - REA Express [2/2], 1965-1969; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rockwell International (North American Aviation), 1941-1983; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - S & H Green Stamp Company, 1961-1966; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Safeway Stores, Inc., 1959; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Slick Airways, Inc., 1964-1965; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Smith Corona Marchant, 1965; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Springmeier Shipping Company, 1957-1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Standard Airways, 1958-1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Standard Oil Company, 1969-1971; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stokely - Van Camp Company [1/4], 1963; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stokely - Van Camp Company [2/4], 1962-1963; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stokely - Van Camp Company [3/4], 1956-1963; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stokely - Van Camp Company [4/4], 1952-1963; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Super Valu Stores, Inc., 1963-1968; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Winn-Dixie Stores, Inc., 1976; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "A Survey of Wages and Major Fringe Benfits in Teamster Agreements with Safeway Stores, Inc.", December, 1971; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Company Profiles & Research 1 of 2: Pabst Brewing-Phillips Morris, 1983; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Company Profiles & Research 2 of 2: Phillips Petro-Proctor and Gamble, 1983; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Safeway Inc.-Prepared by IBT Information Center, August 1986; Series 1 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Recent Developments in Labor Law Booklet, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - REA Organizing Activities, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Survey of Taxicab Contracts Report, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Comparison of National Master Freight Contract Changes, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Senate Hearings, 1981 February 17 - November 3; Series 2; 2 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series cotains materials produced by the Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations dating from February 17 - November 3, 1981. Included are full hearing transcripts as well as reports and individual statement transcripts. Investigation topics include organized crime in the waterfront industry and government efforts to combat labor racketeering.
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 17; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 17; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 18; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 18; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 19; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 19; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 25; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 25; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 26; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 26; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 27; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Organized Crime's Influence and Control over the Waterfront Industry along the East and Gulf Coasts" Hearing Transcript, 1981 February 27; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Teamsters' Central States Pension Fund Investigations Report, 1981 August 12; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Teamsters' Central States Pension Fund Investigations Report, 1981 August 12; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Teamsters' Central States Pension Fund Investigations Staff Statements, 1981 October 27 - November 3; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering Report, 1981 October 28; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering Report, 1981 October 28; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Trascript, 1981 October 28; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 October 28; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 October 29; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 October 29; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 November 2; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 November 3; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Government's Ability to Combat Labor Racketeering" Hearing Transcript, 1981 November 3; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- History Files, 1901-2000; Series 3; 2.5 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains collected Teamsters and general labor history files from the IBT Research Department. The materials date from 1908-2000, and include articles, reports, general correspondence, Teamsters bibliographies and filmographies, news clippings and magazines. Also included is numerous correspondence and legal proceedings produced by the Teamsters' court-appointed Board of Monitors.
  - Articles [1/3], 1939-1989; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Articles [2/3], 1938-1976; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Articles [3/3], 1938-1996; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Articles by Victor Riesel, 1983-1986; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Biographies, undated; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Board of Monitors, 1957-1959; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [1/6], 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [2/6], 1960; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [3/6], 1959; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [4/6], 1959-1960; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [5/6], 1959; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Board of Monitors - Correspondence [6/6], 1958-1959; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Board of Monitors - Legal Proceedings [1/2], 1958-1959; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Board of Monitors - Legal Proceedings [2/2], 1957-1959; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1993; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Detroit Labor News: "Labor is on the March" Special Forgotten Addition, 2004; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Educational Articles, Early 1900's, 1957-1958; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - General Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1958 September 16; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Important Events in American Labor History, A Chronology 1778-1955, US Department of Labor, 1956; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Industrial Relations Reports, 1957-1966; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - International Molders and Allied Workers Local 48 Strike, 1983-1986; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Johnson Controls, Inc., 1991; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Labor Oral History Project, 1986; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Magazines, 1959-1965; Series 3 (Oversize 13, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1954-1988; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reports [1/2], 1957-1960; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Reports [2/2], 1984-1991; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Research Department Indices-Wages, Settlements, and REA statistics, 1939-1955; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Research Dept. Study: "Public Warehouses: Cold and Dry Storage", March 1968; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Strike Certification Card, Switchmen of Pittsburg, PA for Arthur Estep, November - December 1901; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 'Strikes of 1902', Chapter VI, 'The Packing House Teamsters' Strike', ND (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Teamsters Conventions, 1991; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Teamsters Films, 1998; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters History, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Teamsters History Bibliographies, 1986; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Teamsters Trademark Research, 2000; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Union Busting, 1988-1989; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - United Teamsters of America Journal, 1908; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; Series 3 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study-Covering Cartage Agreements of the Eastern, Central, Western and Southern Conferences, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Alcoholic Beverages-Bakery, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Bakery Supply-Box Manufacturers, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Building Construction, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Building Material & Supply, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Building Movers-Dairy, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Drugs-Food Warehouse, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Furniture & Department Stores-Laundry Dry Cleaners, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Linen Supply-Office Employees, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Oil-Paper Wholesale, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Paving & Surfacing-Soft Drinks, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - National Local Cartage Freight Study: Soft Water Service-Wire, 1956-1963; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Joint Council 38-Research Department, 1958-1962; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Calendar Project, November 1985; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Research Bulletin [1], Spring 2002-Summer 2004; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Research Bulletin [2], Fall 2004-Summer 2005; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Laundry and Linen Facts and Trends, 1958-1962; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "Wage-Price Dynamics", undated; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Miscellaneous Reports, 1940s; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Notes Board IBT, 1940s; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Interstate Commerce Commission Research, 1940s; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Notes Board, 1940s; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Morse Board, 1941; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Sharfman Board [1 of 2], 1943; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Sharfman Board [2 of 2], 1943; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Railways Express: Lapp Board, 1948; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: Research Review, June-July, 1959; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: Railway Labor Express News, March 14, 1966; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: Union Labor Report, February 2, 1967; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: Monthly Economic Letter, March, 1967; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: New York Times Article, June 7, 1970; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "Labor Rejects Guidelines, August, 1970; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:Controls Pamphlet, September, 1970; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:The Machinist Newspapers, November 19, 1970; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:The Teamster Magazine, December, 1970; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"A Union View of Inflation", January, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"Talking Price Controls", February 1, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"The Bat in Mr. Nixon's Hand", March 1, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"A Wage-Price Plan", April 5, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"Nixon's Pay 'Guidelines'", May 3, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"The Congressional Record", July 27, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"Treasury Department Press Memo", August 4, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"Business Week Article", October 16, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"General President Letter", November 1, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control:"The Federal Register", November 16-17, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "The Teamster Magazine", December, 1971; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "The Teamster Magazine", January, 1972; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "The Teamster Magazine", August, 1972; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Health and Welfare Survey, 1973; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Teamsters Research Department Files-Wage and Price Control: "The Teamster Magazine", February, 1973; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Teamsters Labor Academy Staff, undated; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Story of American Labor - Oregon State Federation of Labor, 1952; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - "Management Experience in Dealing with the Teamsters" by Industrial Relations Counselors Inc, staff (confidential), Sept 9, 1960; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - NAFTA & Cross-Border Trucking Issues-Significant Research Reports, February, 1999; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - NAFTA & Cross-Border Trucking Issues-Selected Articles on Organizational Positions, February, 1999; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Research Department Agreement Summary Report-Joint Council 10, Local 127, June 28, 2004; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - A Chronology of Unionism with Emphasis on State and Local Employment, 1980; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - A Shared Past: Strikes, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "An Account of a Visitor to Lowell," The Harbinger, 1836, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - An Overview of Federal Legislation that Covers U.S. Workers, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Camella Teoli Testifies about the 1912 Lawrence Textile Strike, 1912, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Child Labor Historical Facts, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Factory Rules from the Handbook to Lowell, 1848, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Labor Quotes, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica: National Recovery Administration/Roosevelt, Franklin D.; Gompers, Samuel, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Preamble of the Mechanics' Union of Trade Associations, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Ten-Hour Circular (Boston, 1835), 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - The Ludlow Massacre, excerpt from Howard Zinn's A People's History of the United States, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - The Story of My Cotton Dress The Child Labor Bulletin, 1914, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - The Voices of Labor: History Speaks "Voices from America Labor Past", 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Two Bits for a Tragic Tale: Walter Finks's The Ludlow Massacre, 1914, 2001; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Day Four: Globalization Agenda, Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 1)
  - Individual Instruction Card: Springfield City COuncilors - Facilitator's Guide - Session 6, Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 2)
  - Sample Program on the Teamsters for Elementary School Children, ND; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 3)
  - Theory Class, CONF 795, Dr. John Barton, ND; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Dinner Address of Franklin D. Roosevelt, September 23, 1944; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 5)
  - Teamsters Union Quiz, March 8, 1995; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 6)
  - Breaker Boys by Mara Lou Hawse, February 24, 1999; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 7)
  - Resolution Endorsing Teamsters Anti-Corruption Plan/Resolution: Project RISE, 1999; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 8)
  - The Teamster Century, December 1999; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 9)
  - The Boys in the Breakers, 1904, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 10)
  - In the Hot Seat: Rockefeller Testifies on Ludlow, May 1915, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 11)
  - Labor: Labor Movement, Origins of, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 12)
  - Labor: Strikes, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 13)
  - Mr. Coal's Story, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 12)
  - Samuel Gompers, First President of the First President of the American Federation of Labor, 1886-1924, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 13)
  - Selected Historical Dates in the US Trade Union Movement, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 14)
  - Teamsters Local Union XYZ Members & Stewards Retirement Planning Seminar Agenda, August 1, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 15)
  - Women in the Workplace: Labor Unions, 2001; Series 3 (Folder 23, Folder 16)
- State Historical Society of Wisconsin Files, 1907-2003; Series 4; 1 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials from the State Historical Society of Wisconsin labor history archive. One half of the series is comprised of printouts of microfilmed correspondence from the American Federation of Labor, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, and other labor organizations, dating from 1907-1952. The other half of the series dates from 1968-2003 and is comprised of guides to SHSW labor history collections and microfilm records as well as correspondence between the Teamsters and the SHSW concerning the creation and operation of the archive.
  - Correspondence: American Federation of Labor, 1907-1910; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Daniel Tobin, 1944-1952; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [1/6], 1927-1939; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [2/6], 1937; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [3/6], 1937-1942; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [4/6], 1939-1943; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [5/6], 1939-1941; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Dave Beck [6/6], 1941; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous Labor Organizations, 1907-1933; Series 4 (Box 11, Folder 9)